

Sarah McGowan Engineer

5 Lynwood Avenue Manchester M16 85Z, Manchester England

+44 0158 247 2199

s.mcgowan@company.co.uk

Skills

- Interpersonal communication
 - Principles of Engineering
 - Problem Solver
 - Analytic Thinking

Skilled and dedicated engineer with 8+ years of experience working on major civil construction projects, including highways, rails and roads. Passionate about the creation of environmentally sustainable structures and committed to delivering the highest quality of work.

Employment History

Civil Engineer, MC Engineers Ltd - Manchester

Jan 2017-present

- Oversee rail team and work on major projects within Manchester, including the £2.9bn Transpennine Route Upgrade (TRU) project.
- Design and plan major structures according to client specifications and legal requirements.
- Exemplary record of project completion within or under budget (87%) and on schedule or earlier (79%).
- Attend regular meetings with clients and contractors to address concerns, questions and ideas.

Assistant Civil Engineer, McWorth's Construction Co. - Manchester Dec 2014-Jan 2017

- Assisted civil engineers with structure design on various projects including the Northern Hub rail project and Manchester Metrolink.
- Commended for timeliness in creating reports and for promptly answering client and contractor queries.
- Supported seven civil engineers with budgets and timescales.
- Visited sites to check on project progress and to discuss concerns with contractors.

Education

Civil Engineering BEng (Hons), University of Manchester

Aug 2010-Sep 2014

- Graduated with honours.
- Achieved Student of the Month Award on four occasions

Volunteer Work

Young Engineers of the Future - Manchester

Aug 2014-present

- Guidance and teaching for after-school club for elementary and high school kids to learn about engineering and build their own projects.